Okay.
Hello, everyone.
So I'm here joined to welcome you and introduce you to how you
can document your work and build your own website
and break the barrier of it's not so scary.
So first thing, I'll just quickly talk about our infrastructure.
We have a few different tools that we're going to use during this course, and
we are hosting all these applications ourselves on our own hardware,
which is currently at the new Fab Hub in Kendall, Boston.
So we're very proud of this because we control the data, we're private, and then
we can make sure that this documentation lives on as long as possible so that your
work can be shared for multiple generations, we hope.
So the
first big platform is the FabLabs.io. It's for the network.
It's listing all our Fab Labs around the world.
It's been around for a long time. And this is a great place to find other
labs as well. And we use this also as a login system because you can have
accounts on here, and these accounts can be logged into other platforms that want
to share with the Fab Lab network. So we're using this sort of single sign-on entry
point. So in a lot of places, when you log into our
applications, you'll be going through the FabLabs.io platform.
You can also visit it to find other labs, and there's also a forum with a wider
network if you want to go there.
The other big platform, which you'll be using a lot for your documentation, is the
GitLab platform we call. It's a hosted Git repository, so this allows-- Git is a
version control system that basically keeps track of all your changes to your
website, and then it provides a web interface so that you can do everything through
the browser, interact with your website.
It also has a code editor, so you can do all your coding within a browser window
and
also interact with it from your computer, and it's just a big collaboration
platform, and we're using it to host all your websites together.
And then this GitLab platform is also automatically building your website every
time you make changes to it. It's building your website and publishing it.
So it's a big tool. We're using a small part of it, and I'll go over it in a bit.
The next one is Nouval. This is our evaluation program that we built specifically
for the Academy programs,
and this allows students and instructors to keep track of each week's
work and make comments, and so that you can--
sort of a central place for all your assessment evaluations.
And then we have Matamos, which you might have already tried to log into.
This is our chat platform. It's a very large software that is used a
lot in security environments, but they have an open source version, which we took
on very early on in its development and we're still using today, and which just
basically allows us to have multiple channels and everyone can talk to each other.
We get notifications, and there's a phone app, and so this is just our personal
platform that we can use to communicate with each other.
Oops. So
let's first check everyone has access.
I saw there was one or two
messages in my Matamos. Some people didn't get an email, but nearly all of you
should have received a student welcome email with your account details.
There's a username and a password.
Unless you already had an account, then there will be no password.
If you don't know your password, it's not logging in, you can try a password reset.
But the first thing is just make sure you find this email.
You can see there's the-- If you can't find it, try and search with the email
address where it comes from.
And basically, let me know.
Actually, I'll share my email address, but let me know if you really have problems
or just ask me now. And then we're going to first, if you haven't
tried already, let's try and log in. So you're going to go to the GitLab.
I was going to try and copy this,
but
I'm going to write in Matamos link in case you want to see it.
So please go here and try and log in. And you won't be using the password field.
You'll be using the little login button at the bottom that says Fab Labs, and this
will take you to the Fab Labs page where you should see a login screen.
And then there is where you put in your username and password that you received in
the email address in your email inbox.
If it doesn't work, you can try and forget password.
If you still don't get any email, yeah, let me know.
You can interrupt me now also if you like.
And if that works, then you get asked a quick question, do you want to allow GitLab
to connect to your Fab Labs account?
And you can say yes, and then with luck, you're in.
And it should look like--
So this is the login screen with the Fab Labs.
And then once you log in, it should look something like this. You're logged in.
But yeah.
I'll
wait a bit if anyone is crying. Any questions there?
Besides maybe not getting email.
I'll wait a bit. Five, four.
With Matamos, it's a very similar thing, except-- Well, it's not similar, actually.
Sorry. There's no FabLabs.io because it doesn't allow us to make that connection.
So you just put in the same login and password you would put for FabLabs.io.
You just put it on the form for Matamos, for the chat application.
And it's the same when you open this in your phone.
It's going to ask you what server you want to use, and you're going to have to put
the same URL that you put in the browser.
So chat.academe.org, and then it will be the same login flow.
You
have to put in-- Oh, this is wrong. You have to put in your username and password.
And the phone is great because then,
yeah, you just get the push notifications a bit quicker.
So it's a nicer flow for
getting your messages on time or having a live conversation.
But the website works great as well. You can also just stick to that.
You can have it open in your browser all the time, and then you'll get the browser
notifications if you have the browser open. So that's quite nice.
So what are we doing? What about your website? How does this all work?
So for documenting your work, we're providing you a ready-made template with
everything you need to get started.
And we'll be using a language called
Markdown that will automatically-- So it's a bit easier to understand Markdown, and
it will convert this into HTML, which is used to make your website.
We'll be using a tool called Zenskie.
I'll talk about it next slide. And
yeah. If you don't know,
HTML code is everything that your browser is reading to build your website.
So everything your browser is communicating with through the servers around the
world, they read HTML. So this looks like on the right.
It's basically a markup language that just describes how to display the content.
So it's
just looking at the image on the right, you say have a title of the page, then you
have a body where the content is. H1 is like the heading, the first heading, and P
is for paragraph. So you have all these kinds of syntax that describe what the
content is. And then the browser reads this HTML and decides how to display it.
The browser is the one that decides how it looks like.
And then we also have a language called CSS as a cascade style sheet,
which is used to
adjust the style that the browser makes.
So, the browser might decide an H1 has got 10 pixels font
size, and they say, "Well, I don't like that," and they use CSS to change that.
So these are the layers. You start with HTML. The CSS is sort of the styling.
So if you would like to go into the HTML, there's a
w3schools.com has a great sort of a tutorial.
I would have a quick play there, just go through there, just at least read it like
a book, just get familiar with all the different elements, so that later on in
working with your website, when you see these things, they won't look so foreign.
And the more you do that, the more you sort of understand what each of these, like
a P tag is a paragraph. Then it starts to become intuitive, and it won't become
scary. And then you'll sort of get excited because there'll be a new error message
or a new thing that doesn't work, and you will get sort of an adrenaline rush by
figuring it out and getting on to the next error message.
So yeah, really enjoy the experimenting and learn to build your own website,
because it's fun when you can start making your own things the way you want as you
envision them. It's going to be a lot of fun.
So we're not going to ask you to make-- making all your HTML is a lot of work when
you're writing text, and your documentation, and your notes.
So we're using a language called Markdown, which is a very simplified
way of just telling text what it looks like.
So this is just a plain text way of saying, okay, these are paragraphs, these are
titles. So if you see like there's a hash, it's like a title, and then it sort of
converts it to, this is what it would interpret those things as.
So,
for example, you have these code little symbols that you put in front of the words
that tell it, okay, this is a title, this is a subtitle.
Then we have italics.
With asterisks, you can say, "This text is italics," and, "This text is bold." So
it's not quite like using a word editor, but it allows you to, with very little
characters, describe what your content is and how to display it.
So you have on the middle column, we have here lists.
So this is how you would show a list and a sub-bullet point.
Images, we have this sort of like exclamation mark and square and round brackets.
This is going to be very important later, and I'll show you a bit, just
a quick overview of what Markdown looks like.
And
then the final piece of the puzzle is to get the whole Markdown and HTML to work
together and to have something that you can publish as a website.
We're using a tool called Zentangle.
Now, this is a nice tool that someone built in the community.
It's an open source tool that's basically converting Markdown into HTML and then
making their own opinionated style.
So as you see on the right, this is
what it looks like out of the box, and it's good for documentation because
everything's in a uniform and there's a lot of features that's geared towards
documenting. This tool is geared towards documenting.
And so in the very basic form, it's just Markdown, HTML, but there's a lot of
little options you can turn on and different features, and so there's a lot to look
into, and we'll play around with it a bit later.
For those maybe previous years and instructors, we used in the previous years a
tool called MKDocs, and it was exactly the same.
The people behind Zentangle made the theme materials for MKDocs.
But unfortunately, MKDocs has sort of become unmaintained.
It's an open source project. They had one developer, and they sort of stopped
working on it, and the
community splintered in different projects, and one of them came out was a
Zentangle project that we've decided to use for your
documentation this year and the future.
Everything's the same. For those of MKDocs, everything's the same.
So if you're looking at previous years, you might see the word MKDocs in other
students' documentation, if you're looking back at other students, and you can copy
those straight. Everything's the same.
It copies over. It's just a different name, and then, of course, new functionality.
So let's start having a look at your website. You can follow with me.
I'm going to go slowly. I suggest if you didn't find your website, a good place to
go is to go to the class website, the
class at Textile Academy,
and then you can go to Participants.
Yeah.
Somebody asked if you can write the URL server for the phone
Mattermost app.
The Chat Academy, I think.
I think this works, yeah. So you just go to Chat Academy. That should work.
Let me know. It's the same one in the browser.
But yeah, if you want to look, find your website or your fellow students, there's a
nice page of all the participants.
So you can go through that and then click your link, and it should take
you to your website. I'm going to open my--
Yeah. But as an example, I just take someone,
and so this is sort of what it looks like.
And then at the top, you can click the little Get button, and it should take you to
your repo.
If you're logged in and you also want to find it through your GitLab.
So I'm in GitLab right now. On the left, you can click Projects or Activity,
and then you should see your project listed here. I have a lot.
So I'm going to open a demo project I made.
And so this is sort of the homepage of your Git project.
So it should have your name at the top, where I have demo here.
So this is the title of the project.
There's the URL to the published website if you would like a quick link.
Below it is the list of the files in your project.
So these are all the files in your project.
At the bottom, there's a sort of a Read Me file, which is
generic. This is for the project, so it's not really related to your website.
This would be for if anyone outside of you comes into your project, they could see
what is this about, and how do I run it, and stuff like that.
Right here in the middle, you'll see my name, and I'll highlight it here with my
mouse. This is sort of the last edit I made, and I have a green
checkbox. This is also saying that my website got published, so everything's
looking good, and we'll dive into that in a bit.
Yeah, I'll open the link to my website. So this is what it looks like.
We have the header, different pages, and then sample document.
If I want to edit a file, you see there's a big code button on the
right.
You can click the drop-down, and you should see find a world called Web Editor.
And when you click that, it's going to open a
code editor in your browser, and so this is where you will be making the changes to
your website.
I'll just check my notes. Yeah.
Sorry, I'll backtrack a bit. I want to also explain a bit, so we use the
word Git, and so GitLab is a wrapper around Git.
Git is tracking all the changes that we make.
So every time, it's basically like if you've ever used the Word document or Google
Sheets, every time you make an edit, it's sort of saved, and you sort of see a
history of all your changes, and sometimes you can revert back.
Git is a bit the same thing,
and we call this commits. So on the left, under Code, I see Code Commits.
If I click it
It's going to load all the changes I made, and it's going to have the date, and
it's going to have a piece of text, my name, who changed it, when.
And so I can go back and I can see all the changes.
I can then open a specific change. So if I open
one of these changes,
then I'm going to see specifically at that date what changed.
And so we sort of have here, there's multiple files.
I'm going to just close this for a minute, and I'm going to show you in side by
side. So this view is sort of showing you the left is what it was and the right is
what it became. And so there's a way to see.
You can go back and see what things have changed, whether you forgot or whether
someone else made a change. You can then go back and see exactly what changed.
So this is the big power of Git and a lot of its users to sort of keep track of
changes in an organized way. So those are called commits.
They're all sequential,
so always the new one is your most recent. That's what's sort of published.
That's what's the latest version, and that's when you edit files, you're editing
the latest version.
You can go back to previous files, so it's called reverting.
That's a little rabbit hole. For small things, you can sometimes open the commit
and just copy the line that you accidentally deleted.
If you made a lot of changes that you want to undo, there's sort of a revert
function, and yeah, that's something you can do your research to do.
So now,
yeah, so this is, as I said, is GitLab.
And to answer the question,
GitLab is a wraparound Git, which means we can also have a copy of this Git
project on our computer. And the great thing about copying this to our-- and it's
not really a copy. Yeah, it's a copy to our computer, is that we can then just work
on our computer without having the internet or without using the browser.
So it can be faster depending on your computer.
And then you get to decide every time you want to make those commits and push them.
Whereas when you're working in a browser, because your window tab can close or
crash or your computer restarts, you're sort of saving every time you make a
change, a bit like Google Sheets. When you're working on a computer, you can do a
full day of edits, as if you're editing some notes or files on your computer, and
then you say, "Okay, I'm ready. I like how it looks." And then we call it push.
You push it back up to the server, and then it sort of syncs with this project.
And you can even work both with the browser and the local, but then you've got to
remember which one's ahead and you've got to keep them in sync.
So Git's designed for that. So yes,
I'll get into it, but I do suggest trying local and we'll-- Yeah.
Okay. So Zinkl is
how the project is organized. So we saw in the repo we had a
TOML file. This is basically how we sort of configure your
personal website. So you can say stuff like the name of the website, the URL it's
under, the colors, the fonts. You can add extra features.
I don't want a table of contents. You
can add extra functionality that's off by default, a lightbox.
And so all those sort of general settings for the whole website happen in this
TOML file.
Then you have the docs folder, and this is where all the content goes.
So this is where all your images, your files, this is where all the notes that you
write in Markdown all go into the docs folder.
And
each of these files is ending in an MD, so as in the next line here.
So as an example, index.md is one of the files that we have Markdown on.
Index is a special word. It means home page.
So index is the only one where if you write index in the URL, so for example,
if I'm looking at my website, I only have a forward slash. You see I have index.
And then
your browser is tricking you because actually what's behind there is index.html.
This is the actual file.
When I have another file, for example, if I open my editor, you'll see there's a
folder called Assignments, and then there's a file called Markdown Week 1.
If I go to Assignments and then Week 1, I will see in my URL also
Assignments and Week 1. But I don't have the HTML.
So the file name that you have in the Markdown, it becomes the URL.
So that's very important to map in your head, and you'll see that as you work
through the weeks.
And then we have this .gitlab-ci file, which is a special file for the project.
This is basically telling GitLab, "Hey, this project is using Zinkl, and
this is how you build the website. This is the command you use and how to upload it
to our platform." So it's very specific to your project, and you don't really need
to change anything there unless something goes wrong or you decide to do something
completely different, use another tool, which is your prerogative.
You can do whatever you want. You don't have to stick to Zinkl.
You can use plain HTML. You can use another tool if you're very familiar with
different tools. We just provide Zinkl because it's very easy out of the box.
So .gitlab-ci is basically telling GitLab how to build your project
and
sort of, yeah. I'll show you. So it's sort of saying, "Okay, we're using Python
because this program is built in Python, and then we're going to install the
required plugins, and then we're going to build your project." So that's very easy.
And then it's just saying everything in the public is we're now in the docs folder,
and we need to build HTML into a public folder.
All right. So let's talk
about the configuration file and try some changes.
The configuration is in a language called TOML, and it's just basically, it's got a
key and value
format. So the first word is always the sort of the setting key, the value you want
to change, and then there's the value which goes in the quotes, which is what you
want the setting to contain. So for example, site name is telling Zinkl, "Okay,
my site name equals," and then whatever you want to call it.
So you can put your name, you can put My Fabric Academy Journey. You can choose.
This is basically deciding. And these values are sort of the ones I suggest you
start with, and you can find them
in the project. If you can't find the word, you just do a search.
If you can't find it, then you can just write it on a new line somewhere.
And basically, you can change your name, your description, and your author, and
these apply to all the pages.
The site URL, I would leave to whatever is written there, because this is basically
the URL you have in the browser. It needs to know what your website URL is, so
don't change that one. A key caveat is that these key settings are
organized into sections. So if you look at site name, it's under the section called
Project in square brackets. And then we have the color, the palette, which is
choosing sort of the default color of
text,
is under project.theme. And then you have the selected font that you want for your
whole website is under project.theme.font.
And so these square brackets are important, and so you can't put site name under
project.theme. It has to go under the correct.
So for example, if I'm going to look at docs.
If I go to their website, I just want to show you an example of-- So I'm going to
their documentation,
and I see, okay, fonts, and I'm reading, because this is what I would do.
I would say, how do I do something? I want to change the font.
And on their documentation, they're showing you, okay, so you need to change
font.text to change the font under it.
So the first thing I would do is in my configuration, I'm going to find this
section in my configuration file if it exists. It might not.
And so if I find this one, then I can put this text right under it.
So this is showing you what you need to change, and you can match it with what you
have. And so it's very important, this sort of structure of square brackets is the
sections, and then sort of the setting, and then two quotes.
Always close your quotes, open and close.
And then you might, if you make a mistake, then your project will fail to build,
and you'll get an error about it. And so
just be, yeah, mindful of those changes of the TOML.
I do link to a little validator that you can do if really you changed something, it
didn't work. There's sort of a TOML checker here you can
try out.
I'm not sure what your--
Dina, what was your question? Password?
Your password for your accounts is in your email.
If you
can't find your email, you can always do a password reset.
So basically, going back,
we run all our accounts on FabLab Zero.
So when you're trying to log in here, you can click the forgot password link and
put in your email address, the one that you sent to coordination.
So that's another way of getting access to your account is to just ask for a, reset
your password. So I would suggest trying that.
See if you get the email. Otherwise, yeah, I'll contact you.
So, if you haven't, while I was talking, tried, you can go to the editor in GitLab,
and I'm going to try now edit the TOML file.
And so I can go to my TOML file if I hit site name, I'll put my name, and
then I can put my...
All right.
I'm also going to change the copyright.
Okay. Well,
what do I do now?
Because we're in the browser, we actually have to-- It's not automatically saving.
We actually have to sort of intentionally commit and push our changes.
So even though we're working in the browser in GitLab, we still have to tell
GitLab, "Okay, I'm finished working on this file.
I'm ready to sort of publish it to my website." And you'll see there's a little one
here, which is basically telling me it's detected that one file changed.
If I open this sort of sidebar, it's a sort of another view tab.
It's listing here this one file is this field TOML.
It's got an M, it means it's modified.
If I click it, it's going to show me what changed.
So you've got a minus and a plus. You've got two lines and showing it sort of the
from to. So it's showing you what it was and what it became.
And so it's like,
I like to just go through, "Okay, yes, I did this." There was no everything looks
good. You can compare the quotes match. It's another double checking.
Especially when changing a TOML, you want to be really sure you didn't forget a
closing tag. And comparing it to the previous
line that changed, it's a good way to see if you missed anything.
Then we have a commit message. This is sort of every save, every commit you do, you
can put a sort of a comment to it, and this is just for you personally.
It will be in the history, and it will be permanent, but it's a good way to know
what was in these commits. So if you're going back and you have a long list of
changes, you don't want to open each one to see, where did I change this file?
So a good thing is to write a message that's good for you. So there's two ways.
You can say, "I updated the TOML file," or you can say, "I changed my site name."
You can be more descriptive, you can just be generic, or you can just say, "One,
two, three." It's up to you. So you can say, "Updated a config file,"
or you can say, "Updated,"
or "Edited my name." You can write what you want.
It's just personally for you, it makes no difference.
And when we're ready with a message, you say commit and push.
But very important, it has to say, "Push to main." Main is sort of,
there can be lots of forks in this project. You can have lots of parallel work.
You can do lots of things together at the same time, and so they call this
branches, but generally 99% of the time, I think you should just work in main.
So always be pushing to main because you only really want to work on one thing at a
time and not have to deal with merging things together.
So always make sure it's committing to main.
If it doesn't say main, you can click the drop down and then select something else.
Let me know if you don't see main. You can comment me now or raise your hand.
So when you click commit and push, it's going to double ask you, are you sure?
Because,
but we're sure. We always want to connect.
I think after this, the first time, it won't ask you again.
So you're just like, "Yes, I want to commit to the main branch."
And that should go through.
And then, so you're thinking, okay,
I'm now going to reload my commit list. I'm back on my project.
Where's the refresh button? I'm going to refresh this page,
and I'm going to see this is the new commit I made 19 seconds ago, update config,
and I'm going to have the green check mark.
Now let's dive into what this check mark is.
It's related to every time you make a commit or you push from locally, we're going
to actually build your project. And so, this is called a CI pipeline or
pipelines, and it's basically for every commit you make, it's going to run that
code that we had in that .CI YAML file in that if you saw in your project.
So it's basically building your Zekel project, and you always want it to pass.
So if it fails, then you sort of open it, you click-- it's going to have a red
error message. And if you click it and go into it, you're going to see this deploy
pages. It's called Pages. So we're going to click into it, and then you're just
going to see a bunch of logs. This is sort of the server building your project,
downloading the Zekel website and installing it, and then downloading your code.
And then...
So in my scenario, it's just successful.
It's going to always be successful, but if it fails, then you will sort of at the
bottom of this list of sort of the logs of the server building your project, it
might have error. We couldn't find an image, or the TOML file had an error.
And so sometimes these errors are a bit cryptic. I go back to that meme.
It's like, what's this error mean?
And so that might be a good-- That's good to read the error message, try and find
the error message, and look at the commits. What did I actually change?
Go back to see what you actually changed.
Google it or ask AI, what's this error mean?
And then not how do I fix it, but what does it mean?
So then you can actually try and fix it yourself and sort of have that.
So, keep in mind, it's always going to work, but if the pipelines you have to have
in the back of your head, every commit is going to be building your project in a
pipeline, on a server, and sometimes it may fail.
So you'll always make sure that if your website doesn't seem updated, double-check.
Did I get the green mark? Was it correct, or did it fail?
Sometimes you get an email that it failed as well.
Yeah. So, just for fun, I'll check up,
and I should have my name. Yeah, I have my name now, so it worked.
I think I'll also show you-- So, just double-check my slides where I am.
Google Fonts. Yeah. So, I
don't know where fonts are, so I can just do a Apple+F. I can do Find.
And so I'm searching within this editor. I can do fonts, and there we go.
Theme fonts here. So these are Google Fonts.
You can go to google.com or
fonts.google.com, I think.
And basically, you can look through these fonts and find something you like, so you
can sort of already have something suited to your style just by changing the font.
So that's something easy to do that you can already do today.
And then you would put the name of the font in this setting inside the quotes,
commit it, and the font should change.
You can read the documentation of Zekel if you want to see, how can I use the font
that's not in Google? You can
import your own fonts, but make sure their sort of licensing is free, not doing
paid stuff.
Yeah, I see here you can also change the icon.
So the icon is this thing next to my name.
I've got a little book librarian, an open book.
So if you open the Zekiel docs, and actually there's a link here, so you can
already open it. They have a full library of icons, and then you can choose an icon
you want, and you replace it here.
So there's a lot of settings you can go through and change.
There's here social media. You can put your own social media links here, and then
they will appear at the bottom. So it's something you can already do.
You see at the footer, there's the links.
You can add your own. So if I want what's not on here,
LinkedIn, I don't know. So you make another line, and then you write
LinkedIn as a brand. I guess that icon exists, and then you change the URL.
And so that's how you would make another one.
Let's look at some markdown. If there's no questions,
I'm going to open week one.
Let's get to some real documentation.
I don't know how I am on time, but
this is what markdown looks like. So each week, we just give you a template.
So we just provide a bunch of
useful tips, but this is also an example of how you would do stuff.
So if you see here, what this is all text. It's all special to Zekiel.
I've got some HTML. If you can see here, this is HTML.
So you're mixing HTML and markdown. So this is an image.
I'm just going quickly through it now. And I know this.
So yeah, it's good, and I'm going to match it to what I see here.
So, for example, this weekly assignment was this nice little collapsible box with
one objective. So if I go back to the markdown, I see the double hash.
So that was the title. So that's a
heading or subheading because it's number two.
The first hash is the title of the page, and that also becomes the link in the nav
bar. So it's a two-in-one. And then these special boxes are these, they're called--
I forgot what they were. Ammonitions.
So
in Zekiel, I won't go through them all, but there's a lot of different extra
features that you can add to your website.
So, markdown is, let's say, the bare minimum.
It's like the headers, the bullet points, the paragraphs.
But sometimes Zekiel provides you already-made objects, like the little collapsible
things. You have little buttons
that you can then,
if you enable it, so if you follow their settings, they say, "Okay, you need to
make sure this is in your toml file." And then buttons look like this when you do
it this way. So this is, for example, a button.
I have to copy this whole piece of thing in my markdown, and then if it works, it
will look like this. So instead of a link looking like this one
up here,
it's going to look like this. So they have a lot of things.
They have code blocks, diagrams. They have tables which are very useful for you.
So you would then just say, "How do I enable it?
What they look like?" Their documentation is great, so just go through it all,
and
then you put it here.
Yeah.
So Zekiel is reading markdown files.
So week one.md is a markdown file. So, the base is markdown.
So we're starting with markdown. And then Zekiel is adding their own little extra--
So there's markdown. I can add HTML, which is not markdown, but I can add
HTML. So if I want my own
image, whatever. If I want to write my own
paragraph, I can write it in markdown, or I can write it in my own way.
And then these things are
Zekiel's custom components, custom elements that they've made for you that so
instead of having to build the whole HTML and the CSS yourself, we've made it for
you already. And all you have to do is they come up with these
special symbols like question mark, question mark task is going to open a little
blue box, but that's not markdown. That's really specific to Zekiel.
So it's this mix, like sprinkling extra cherries on top of the markdown.
Because markdown is a very simple language that's interoperable between any
tooling. And so it's great here, but because we're really only using it to build a
website and only with this tool,
we can add this custom. So all these things I showed you in the Zekiel
documentation, they're very custom to Zekiel, this part.
That's why you have to enable them with these--
You see these extensions, they're called.
You're extending the markdown with these extra functionalities.
And sometimes there's stuff outside of Zekiel, so you may find also a
markdown extension on another website, or someone made one on GitHub,
and
it's not guaranteed to work, but it could work, if it's supporting the markdown
to go down. Yes, it's a Python markdown, so it's a specific version, but you can
extend it. So there's lots of plug-ins, especially a lot of the markdown extensions
from MK Docs should also work if you don't find it here.
Yeah.
You got it right. Write markdown, then you can add some Zekiel custom elements on
top, and then when you push it, it builds your website.
And
actually, what you're missing is in the mix.
So
just like in this template, we have markdown, we have some custom, very
specific elements that are from Zekiel,
and we have at the lower down here, we had-- This is HTML.
So, for example, this one is about having a caption on your image.
Actually, I should talk about image, though.
An image in markdown just looks like this,
but there was no support for a caption.
And so we're using HTML to basically say, I want to add some caption.
If we look at what it looks like here.
So you see it's an image, and it has a text underneath.
So to do that, there was no way in markdown, there was no way in Zekiel.
So this was the way in HTML. And so you can add it, or sometimes you find a
nice-looking button
on the
internet, and you can copy the HTML on and it works.
Because HTML is also like markdown. It works everywhere.
The only thing that's really specific to Zekiel is these specific
elements.
Yeah, I think good one is so about images.
This is the markdown for an image. So you've got a exclamation mark, two
square brackets, and two round brackets.
The first part is saying, "I'm an image." The square brackets is actually saying
what this image about, and it's called an alternative text.
And these are usually predominantly used for screen readers of blind or deaf
people. Well, blind people. So that their computer can
describe what this image-- Well, read the text.
So, for example, if I upload a picture of me or a picture of trees, I can say it's
a picture of a pine tree. So then whoever's reading your documentation, they
understand, okay, this is a pine tree.
So it's nice to put an alternative text, and that goes in the square brackets.
And in the round brackets, you put in the location of that image relative to where
you are. So you've got to tell, if you think of Zekiel as reading this page and
say, "Okay, I'm here. I'm in week one.md.
Where is this image?" So you have to tell it, "Okay, well, actually, you're inside
the assignments folder now." So you have to go outside the assignments folder, find
a folder called Images, which we have down here, and in there, you'll see I have a
folder called Avatar Folder. So how do we go back?
And actually, the weather is quite nice right now. So back is two dots and a slash.
That means go back one folder. And then, so now we write images
And then I write a slash, so that's the end of the folder.
And inside images, we have avatar, and then I write the name of the photo,
JPEG. There. So this is going back one folder, then go inside images, and then the
name of my image. So if I put all that together because we're not supposed to have
spaces,
then that's my image.
And how do I know it works? Well, do I have to commit it?
Well, you have to commit it, but a quick way of validating your markdown, which
really only works for the markdown, is on the right here.
On the top right, you see a little
two columns in a magnifying glass.
If you click it, it's going to show you a preview of your markdown.
So the web editor is able to render markdown, only markdown.
So you'll notice that the Zekiel stuff doesn't work.
The little blue boxes, styled boxes don't work.
But it's a great way for verifying the images work, your headings, things look
roughly away. So it's a nice way to look. So you see here, I made image.
If I
misspell my image name, it doesn't work. I get picture of pine tree.
Basically, that's saying, "I couldn't find image, so I'm going to show you the alt
text,
JPEG."
Yeah.
So having the in-browser, it's a nice one,
especially for experimenting now.
For the markdown, to play with the markdown, you don't need to commit everything.
You can just play with everything here, and you'll see a live preview.
So that's on the right side.
The good thing about this editor actually is with the images, so exclamation mark,
two squares, and then I do the round braces.
I'm going to go back two folders, and you'll notice the editor is actually helping
me. So it's telling me, "Okay, you want to go back." So it's showing me I can,
within the editor, choose a folder. I don't have to write it myself.
And then, so I'm going to click Enter on my keyboard.
I click Enter, and then I say, "Okay, I'm going to look for the image." I want to
go in week two, and then I say, "Yep, that's the file I want." So it's helping me
build
my path within Markdown. So that's a great way to help you don't make mistakes with
the file names.
But how do we get an image in there?
Well, if we go to the image folder, you find it, you right-click it.
You can see there's an Upload button.
So you can click Upload, and then you can choose an
image.
Hang on a bit.
Just give me a moment. I don't have an image to upload, but if I go to week one
and I say Upload,
then I can...
There we go. It's the same name. I already had this image, but it's sort of just
uploading. It's showing you how to upload an image.
And then I can also choose to rename this image, so I can then right-click the new
image I just uploaded, click Rename, and say My New Image.
It's good to rename images because maybe you took it with your phone or something,
it's got a weird name. I would suggest to write a good name, and I also always
suggest that it should have no spaces in it because websites don't work well with
spaces, so you don't want to write new space like this.
I also wouldn't suggest capitals. Keep everything lowercase.
It's just very simple, and it's less likely to make mistakes.
And websites also don't like capital case. It just gets weird.
So if you keep everything lowercase, it's just less likely to make errors later on.
There are some questions on the chat.
What?
You have some questions at the chat.
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah, so if I got this new image now, actually I can even drag it now. No, I can't.
That was too good to be true. Okay.
I'm going to go back here.
Week one as an example. New image. I've got it selected.
And then on my alt text, I can put in the square brackets.
There we go. Don't forget to commit. We look on the left.
We have three files we need to commit. So we got the week one.
I'm going to open it. It's going to show me the changes. Yeah, two new images.
I've got the new image I am uploading, and then, yeah, new image uploaded.
I write a message, and then I click Commit to push.
That's it. That should
then
now if I go back to my...
So there's a question here about right-clicking.
We have to make sure we're clicking the folder, and sometimes I notice on some
browsers, it's like a right-click
and then clicking it again. So if you don't get this pop-up because you get the one
of the browser, sometimes just doing a quick click on the link on the week one
again can work. If that doesn't work, select week one.
So you see I have it highlighted in the left here.
Then at the top, you'll see
this sort of...
Oops. If we go to the top here,
I'm pretty sure you can do...
No, this is new folder, new file.
Hmm.
Can you go back to the original settings in the original Zankio file?
You mean you want to revert?
If you think you've made a mistake in a Zankio file, you can go to your project.
So if I go to my main page build project, I can look at the list of files.
I can then click
the Zankio TOML file, the configuration file, and so I'm looking at the current
version of it. If I go to History, I can click here, History.
I can see a list of all the changes I've made just to this file.
And so by that, I can then, for example, in my case maybe,
your case, you will go to the first commit, let's say, creating the
template. I have a big history, so I'm just going to go to the one from today.
And then if I look at this commit, I can then say, "View this file." View the
whole file for this specific commit that I wrote four hours ago.
And then I can copy the whole contents.
There's a little button here that says Copy Contents.
And I can then just paste the whole contents into my
editor
and overwrite everything. And then I'll see here, okay, it's changed.
And I can see, okay, now it's going back from Julian to that generic placeholder
name. So that's one way you could go back and undo things.
If you really want to go more,
if you want to go hardcore, there's revert.
I don't know if in Git, there's a lot of powerful tools to just go back in history
and just go reverse your commits. And so, for example, I can then click this commit
that I looked at previously.
And then in the options on the top right, there's sort of an Options Revert.
Now, so this is going to basically roll back the whole project back to this commit.
So all the previous commits you did, even to other files, they'll get undone, and
it'll go to whatever the state of the whole repo was when this commit was made.
So basically, if you do a bunch of changes and it's all breaking, you don't know
where you are, you can just go back to yesterday was working.
So I'm just going to go back to yesterday, and you undo everything you did.
So it's a very nuclear reaction
Actually, that's not true. That's
reset, which you can't do through here. Sorry, I misspoke.
There's two ones. There's the rollback, but this is actually revert.
So this is
going to reverse. So instead of copy and pasting what I just did, I can just
click this, and it's going to make a commit
for me. So what I was doing where I copy the contents in and make a commit
manually, this one's just going to do it for me.
So if you see here now it made a new commit saying revert.
So this is just reverting a specific commit.
And I can see here
that
all the jobs are failing also.
No, I'm just checking my server.
So I hope that's explaining something.
So, if one commit's making changes of seven files, that's a quick way of reverting
a bunch of files.
So then the more nuclear option of rolling back your whole commit, you have to do
it locally in your computer. And I think if you want to go down, that's very
interesting. So the thing with the web editor is every time I make a change, so
let's say I'm making a change to a markdown file,
even sometimes with these, like this one, I don't know what it looks like.
I don't know how it's going to look like.
I have to commit it, wait for it to build the project, which is like 10, 20
seconds, and then I can see what it looks like on my website.
So
if I would work locally on my computer, if I would download this project and
install it on my computer, then I can install Zikulo on my computer, and I can run
it locally in my browser without having to make commits.
It's sort of running the website locally.
It's going to build the project on your computer, and you can open the HTML files.
You'll see the HTML files, and you can open them in your browser and see what it
would look like without making any commits.
And then once you're very happy with all the changes, maybe it's a full day of
work, then you can make one big commit.
So that's another way of working, and it's nicer because then you don't have to
work in a browser. It depends how fast your computer is.
Sometimes, the editor's a bit slow if you're doing all your changes in here.
But if you're making one spelling mistake, commit, wait.
One upload file, wait, commit, and then it can be quite a slow progress.
So
I either learn the
markdown and try and do all your changes and upload three images and add them,
write some text, and then commit because it sort of guess.
You'll start to see a pattern. You know that this image is going to look like this,
especially after the first and second week.
You'll know the kinds of layouts you want to do.
If you always like an image on the right or you always like blue buttons, then
you're going to copy that blue button every time, and you don't need to commit to
see what it looks like. You can do a bunch of work and then commit.
So it's just speeding up your time.
Yeah. I've also noticed the
GitLab is a bit slow. I think it's always that with this class, everyone's trying
everything at the same time, and so then the server's just especially busy.
So I think if some things are failing, I notice my pipeline has failed.
This is a good example. I can go back and I'm going to open this, why did
my
website not build? And I can see I got an error.
Oh, so you see this is a good way. So I'm looking.
Okay, so it could not render blah, blah footer.
Okay, well, I didn't change anything in the footer, but blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then social. Oh, social.
Then it's looked in icons, and now I read down the text, LinkedIn.
I did do something about a LinkedIn, and it looks like I didn't
write LinkedIn correctly or...
So this is sort of an example of how I would interpret these errors.
They're not going to tell you exactly what's wrong. You sort of have to guess.
What's the website trying to do is trying to build the footer, and then it trying
to read the configuration file, and it can't find something.
And so I remember I did something with the TOML file.
So if I go back to my TOML file,
I can then find social, yeah, down here.
And
oh, I already reverted it.
Maybe not. I didn't commit it. Commit.
This is a good example. Everyone, look, I have this message here that says, "The
file has changed while you're editing it." So I had this tab open, and I
remember I did the revert. So let's imagine I had another tab, and I edited a file,
or I did something locally, and I pushed those commits.
Now this tab is telling me, "Actually, you're not on the latest version.
There's other stuff has happened to your project while you had this open." So it
cannot commit those changes because the place where it's the changing from to is
different. It's like, wait a minute, I might override something you already did.
So the only thing here is to reload the whole tab, so I will lose my changes.
But luckily, it's only one file, so I can copy it, and then I can just reload the
whole page.
And this is kind of another reason why working locally
has advantages because, losing work is less of an issue because they're
just files on your computer until you commit and push them. A browser can crash.
I get something like this that I have to
reload my tab, and I could lose work.
So that's sometimes why people commit often when they're in the tab.
But if you run locally, it's...
I don't know how I am from time, anyone.
I wanted to just quickly talk about that there's also CSS.
So,
Zikulo is going to make...
Ah, this is the problem someone was talking about.
I'm going to push ahead.
If I open my repository, I think the server's quite busy.
Yeah. It's very busy.
Inside the docs folder, there's a file called stylesheets and extra
CSS. In here, you can then customize the
styling that the Zikulo template uses.
So, they decide to have font sizes of this, or the headings and buttons
look like this. And so we can use CSS to sort of change that, so changing the
default that Zikulo uses.
And so these are the CSS, just very quickly, it sort of has these sort of targets.
These are saying, find any element in the HTML that has this sort of
tag on it, so that each element you can assign tags called, well, they're called
classes. I should call them class.
And so it's telling me, find an element on HTML with this class and then change
the default color.
So these are called CSS variable colors, and in the Zikulo documentation, you can
find some
of the defaults, so you can change them.
A good way, I'm going quick, but you have to sort of go down the rabbit hole of
CSS. So if I open my... This is in the browser, so I've got a new developer tool.
I right-clicked, and I did inspect.
And so I'm actually looking at the HTML for this
element. So right, so it's a list. LI is a list.
It's got a class called MD nav link item.
And then I can also see here all the CSS that's applied to it. It's got no padding.
It's got no styling. It's not got much because it's just a list.
And it's got a font size of 0.7.
So now I can say, "Well, actually, I want the list to have a different styling." So
then I can write here at the top, I can write font size, and then I can write,
well, make it 0.8 or 0.1. And
say, "Yeah, I like this font size." So then you say, "Okay, well, I've got to copy
this and then put it in the CSS file." And then you've also got to copy the MD nav,
and then you would say, like...
Of course, it's not working
I shouldn't have reloaded.
And so you put it in here, you put in MD nav, and then you put it the second line
in the font. So instead of this, you put font size.
So what I was experimenting-- This is an experiment, right?
I'm doing it live in the browser, so if I reload, I lose this font size seven.
But this is a great way to, I can manipulate my website in here, do some
experiments with CSS. Your mind will get blown if you get into CSS.
It's really straightforward. The wording is font size, padding, margins,
background. So it's quite intuitive and I think just sort of finding how you can
target it. And that's how you can take your website visually, make it a bit
different, sort of get a bit more advanced.
And, yeah, I really suggest doing some very simple tutorials on the internet, like
W3Schools has great CSS tutorial or ask your AI, "Please explain
me CSS. Teach me CSS." Right? "Don't do something for me, just teach it to me." And
then try and figure out, okay, now that I know how to change a color in the
background, how would I make my own button? Sort of, yeah.
Again, I think working locally is really-- I'm going to quickly show you.
If you look at the documentation on Zekio, they'll explain you how to install
locally. It's very simple. You just need Python.
For example, on Mac, we have Python.
You just need to run these commands to then sort of initialize Python and then
install Zekio. And then when you do Zekio build, you do local host, which is
basically opening a website just on your computer. It's not on the internet.
And then you can see your website. So every time you edit a file, your website
updates. So it's a great way,
but you'll have to clone it, and so to clone it...
I'm going to look if there's any more questions before I get into that.
Yeah, so a commit is the actual saved change.
So that's a specific change from old to new, left to right.
And the jobs is sort of the work that needs to be done every time you make a
commit. So the commit is the change, and the job is actually building your website.
So they have to go in together. That's why we want the job is the green light.
When you have the green light, then the job completed successfully, and it
published your website.
Usually, you don't need to know anything about both.
The commits is like, if I need to go back and figure out what went wrong or what
do I want to change, or what did I accidentally delete, then you would go back into
your list of commits, the history, and see what may have gone, find
whatever. And the jobs, you only care about the most recent one.
So if you make seven commits and six of them fail, but the last
one passed, that's all that matters.
If
you make six commits and all five of them pass, but the last one failed, that's the
problem. It's always the last one, the most recent one, because on the website, you
can only have one website. So it's always the last job that ran that will sort of
publish the website, the truth.
So yeah.
About cloning, again, yeah, I really suggest cloning.
There are some great tutorials on how to clone for yours or whether Mac or Linux.
You could look at the documentation of GitLab.
So that's the software you would use, so their documentation shows you how you can
set up Git on your computer to be able to link
GitLab, our server repo, and your computer.
You have to use a thing called SSH keys. So that's something you'll get into.
And then you can create an SSH key on your computer that then GitLab knows, and
then you can talk to each other. So if you look at the GitLab or the GitHub's
documentation, it's sort of the same idea.
And then what you're doing is you're going to code.
You see this big black box that's code, and you say clone.
You want to clone with--
Well, with SSH, it's a bit hidden now because I'm zoomed out. There.
You want to copy this link, and then when you run...
I'm in a terminal now. You have to open Terminal.
I can go to a folder or something, and I'm going to do Git
clone, and I paste the URL, and then it should just clone it to my computer.
So it's sort of downloading the whole copy of the whole repository with all the
history. So every single change I ever made to this repository is now on my
computer as well.
And
so here's it. So if I look at the file, the file is here, so I can then CD change
directory, Fabry Academy. So I'm now inside the repository.
I can do a Git status. I'm looking at, okay,
what did you change in this file? I can then, as an example, I'm going to just--
You will open your own text editor. I'm just opening an editor in this browser.
Don't
worry about this. I'm just quickly editing a file so
I can then save it. So now I saved it.
If I do Git status, so now on my computer, it's telling me I have one modified
file. This is just on my computer. If I see what changed, show me the difference.
It's showing me, okay, in this file index, this file changed,
and then I can make a commit. So I can say add.
Say, if you want to add this file to be committed, yes.
And then I say, "Okay, Git status." These are the files that will be
committed. I do commit M, I.
And then I can do a Git push, and then I do a Git push.
So this is the same bit what I was doing in the browser.
So if I can choose the file I want. Well, I couldn't choose in the browser, but I
have to choose it here. I commit, and then I push it,
and then it's successful. It's successful because I already made an SSH key on my
computer, so my computer's already connected with the server.
And so, yeah, as you can see, it's not me. I used someone else's computer.
So I made a commit. I still have a failed project, it seems.
I didn't fix my previous one.
Yeah. Kim, and if you're continuing
students, you may see MK Docs. That was the project we used
last year. Everything's the same, except it's a YAML file and not a TOML file.
But the same concept, the same features are there.
You just have to look at the documentation for the material MK Docs theme.
And then
share it. So yeah, I want to show, yeah, how can I run it?
I showed you how to commit. So on a Mac, the easiest way to--
Your Python's already installed, so you don't need to install it, you just need to
activate it. And the best way is to sort of write these commands.
So this is telling me I want to activate Python.
You do this inside the project that you cloned, and then you need to activate
it.
You activate it, and then I have to do pipe install Zekico.
It's
installing Zekio on my computer.
I'm going to paste it in the commands if anyone wants to try.
So I know this works on Mac.
And now if I do Zekico
serve,
this is basically going to just say, "Make me a website and run it on my computer."
Now, I still have that error with the...
Sorry, I'm looking for that, what was it? Twitter?
I still have these social things. I'm going to delete them.
I'm going to save my file.
Oh, I don't even need to commit it because I'm locally, so I just need to then now
serve again. I click serve. Zekio serve.
Great. It's now building me a website.
So if I now right-click, and I say open link
Yeah. And I'm going to have to copy this.
So you see my screen now? I'm on localhost. I'm not on any website. I'm not domain.
This is all on my computer. Localhost is just locally, my website's running, I can
make a change. Oh, I have to open a new tab.
So right now the server's running. I can't write any commands.
It's running the server. So I need to open a new tab in the terminal.
This won't be an issue if you're using an external browser like
VS Code or Sublime or any tech code editor.
I'm just doing everything in the browser to be quicker.
So if I say, "Hello" now, and I save it, if I go
back to the browser... Oh, they're already reloaded. So see?
"Hello." It's much quicker to just try stuff out.
Putting in the work, the rewards are much better later on.
So if you work to set up everything now.
The hardest part is the SSH key. So you've got to go to your account.
In the top right, you'll see your account preferences,
and then you have to go to Access and SSH keys.
This is necessary because Git doesn't really work well with a
username and password. You can get it to work, but I think SSH keys are
my advice because it's sort of a cryptographically secure way of just
making a link between your computer and the server.
It's not a link, it's
sort of a custom password just for your computer.
So in this thing, you can click Add New Key, and just
click the Learn More. And if you look at the Learn More, it's going to GitLab's
website, or actually, the documentation.
And if you scroll down, something will say Generate, and there's a command you can
use to generate your SSH key. You might already have one from
GitHub or something. You can use it.
You don't have to make a new one on your computer.
If you already have a key, it's even maybe better just to reuse it.
The key is you only want to put the
private key. So if we look here, so this is where we're creating it, adding your
key. You sort of need to find a .pub version of it.
And then you paste in here, give it a name, give it a long expiry date, like next
year, so it doesn't stop working while you...
And then you say Add Key,
and then you can test it by doing a Git pull. So when you do the Git clone, sorry.
Any more questions?
That was very fast with SSH. Yeah.
I think, even read this document. Read this sort of explaining what keys are in
your time, I think,
so you'll understand what's going on.
And I'm going to have a look at, so if my pipeline, did it pass?
Any more questions?
There's
a little documentation page that I put in chat.
Your documentation already has markdown examples, but this is sort of
another way to sort of some how-tos, how to edit a file, what it looks like, some
markdown examples, some optimizing, customizing.
We went over it, but this is sort of a mini handbook for some Git if you have extra
issues. The best place is to just go to Mattermost, and there's a specific
channel for
this class. I think it's zero zero Git, something like this.
You should have been added already.
And, yeah, try and break stuff and see.
Any questions?
I'm also going to add the Zekio documentation link.
You can also start by going through their website and seeing all the different
things you can do, trying it out in it.
So I should put basic on there.
There's also like
you can change the way the navigation works.
You can have a sidebar, and
you can have it without the sidebar.
You
can have multiple levels,
and even the documentation is nice because it shows you what it would look like
with the setting or without.
Okay.
Yeah.
Shiva?
Yes. Hi. So I have been following almost everything else.
It's just that upload images or file issue is the thing I'm
facing a problem with. I'm clicking on the week
zero one or week zero two, but it is just showing me option to paste.
I think the drop-down menu is flashing for a moment, but then for some reason, it
is going out. I tried it, so I'm using Mozilla Firefox.
I tried it in Chrome as well. Same thing is happening.
Yeah. I think it's
not the browser, it's like the operating system.
Have you tried doing a right click and then a click?
Like right click and then do one click, a left one. A right click and a, yeah.
Yeah, let me just try that again.
Because I reproduce it now. See, I also see paste. Yeah.
Wait. So you right click once and, yeah, paste. And after that?
And then I, again, click not on paste, but on the file, the folder
again.
Just once.
Okay. I'll try that.
Okay, so I can see a drop-down for a bit of a moment, and then it
goes out.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm also looking. There should be a way to...
Or is there just an alternate way to upload stuff?
There is, yeah. So the alternative way is if you're in your
project, you have to go to the folder,
navigate to the folder, so for example, Images, and week one, for example, and then
on the right here, we'll have...
Oh, the plus sign here. There's a plus sign here, and you can say Upload File.
It's a manual, so it's one file at a time, but it works. Yeah.
Okay. Yeah. Okay. So it's like GitHub one.
Yeah.
Okay. Sure then. Yeah.
Yeah. And otherwise, really the next step, a little bit of work is doing this
locally, because then- You don't have to deal with the browser, and you can add
files to a folder and commit lots of files at once.
So if you feel up to it, the local, and make an SSH key, local
cloning, installing Zekil, it's great because then you don't have to, like, yeah,
select a file-
Yeah
... upload it, select, yeah.
Okay. Yeah. So I just do locally.
This for today, yeah.
Upload and then, yeah. Oh, actually, you can upload lots of files.
Oh, okay. Right. Yeah. Thanks.
All right. Yeah. I don't know. Should we stay longer? Any questions?
You want me to show anything again?
You want me to...
On the left side, yeah, you've got code, which is a repository of all your files,
commits is all the commits. Builds, you've got the pipelines and the jobs, so you
can see a list of all the jobs.
But again, only the last, the most, the top one matters.
So as long as that one says passed, then everything works.
If you have
continually
problems with the pipeline and you think, "I don't think it's me, the pipeline, it
could be the server," let me know. You ask me, "Mattheos, is there something wrong
with the server?" And that sometimes happens.
And I'll look into it. Or I can also help you look at your logs. It's not a...
Okay, my editor works again, so I can show you Zekil.
There was a question about just showing changes.
So if I make an edit,
let's change
the font.
Well,
I don't know. What's this one called?
Robot Condensed. I'm taking it from the URL.
So I copy the font name, and I go down to...
Where was the font?
I'm going to search for font. There it is. So I'm going to put Robot Condensed.
I don't want the plus. It's just a space bar. The space is fine.
Make sure I've got the open and closing quotes, text equals.
I can see there the line changed. Oops.
And so then I see on the left side a one, so it's telling me one file has changed.
I click on it, and I open the new tab, which shows me the list of files that
changed.
And then I write and change font, and I commit to main. I click Commit to main.
And then it should say successfully.
You should see that pop up at the bottom there.
Yeah. The change has been committed. I now go back to my jobs.
On the other tab, I had the list of jobs.
I can refresh this page,
reload the page,
and it says Commit just now, and it said it's passed.
So it says green, so that knows everything's correct.
So if I go to my website
and I
reload my website, it should look different.
I think so. Yeah.
And that's a bit fast. Okay.
Yeah. Helps. So I hope that makes sense. I hope everyone has fun committing.
Look at the markdowns that we've provided you. There's a lot of tips there.
There's a lot of
example markdown you can use. There's the Zekil website. Make commits.
Once you get somewhere exciting, you can then try cloning locally.
Yeah. As mentioned, maybe with Claudia,
especially with uploading images, you have a fixed file storage,
which is 500 megabytes for the whole
class.
So, you've got to make a budget every
week. You've got to decide how many images can I upload and how big each image can
be before I reach my limit. Because if you get to 100 megabyte already today,
you're not going to have space for later on,
which is why optimizing your images is very important, because the smaller you get
them now, the more space you have later on.
And so here, I'll share the slides later, and you can read this in more detail,
sort of suggesting some good defaults. Images can be on your phone.
You're taking really large pictures that have a lot of information, but for a
website, they can be very small. They don't need to be wider than 800 pixels.
A hundred kilobytes is more than enough because you're going to have a lot of
pictures on your website. The website is already fixed width because of the style.
And
also think about not everyone's going to have maybe fiber optics cable or a
satellite connection. People might be looking at this on their phone with not a
good connection. Some countries don't have good connections, and so you have to
also think about that, that if you load a website with very large images, they
can't even look at your website. So, get a workflow.
Claudia sent some suggested apps and things.
Once it becomes part of your rhythm, then,
yeah.
Okay.
I'll see you in nine months.
Thank you.
Thanks a lot. Bye bye.
Thanks. Bye. Thank you.
Thank you very much. Have a nice day